FAJAR SURYA UTAMY

085226071028 | fajarsurya2739@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/fajarsuryautamy | https://fajarsuryautamy.github.io/Fajarsurya_portofolio/
Yogyakarta, Daerah Istimewa Yogyakarta

Civil Engineering fresh graduate with a GPA 3.81/4.00. I spent of my collage years being involved in several activities in organizational, training certification, and Internship. Fast learner & have a great interest and experience

in the Planing Construction, BIM Structure, quality control, Drafter with Autocad and I very interested to working in the mining sector. I am an adaptive person in a diverse environment, target oriented, and always loved to develop myself further.

Work Experiences

PT. Tohoma Mandiri - Project Construction of the wastewater

Mar 2024 - Present pipeline network for the IKN (MTBM)

Engineering

The construction of this wastewater pipeline network is being carried out by PT. Wijaya Karya - HK, KSO. This project involves the installation of 1,300 meters of pipeline using the MTBM (Micro Tunneling Boring Machine) method.

- · Preparing work-related data such as drawings and soil investigation reports
- · Supervising the work of 9 workers
- Communicating, discussing, and meeting with the client (main contractor) regarding the work
- · Preparing and reporting documents related to the work
- Planning the work schedule, manpower, and daily progress plans
- Providing answers and suggestions for any issues that arise during the work process
- Constantly reminding all crew members about safety while working

Methapora Solusi Global - Jakarta

Aug 2023 - Present

Engineer Structure Planing

I was Assigned working as a Planning Structure With Etbas Software, the construction project of Office Griya Cahya a in the South Jakarta

- · Planning Structure Office Griya Cahya on 6 Story
- Make a Report Structure and Make a Drawing Engineering Design Structure

Ditjen Kementerian Pekerjaan Umum dan Perumahan Rakyat

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

(PUPR) - Lampung, Indonesia

Tenaga Fasilitator Lapangan (Field Facilitator)

Internship activities within the MBKM program at the Kementerian Pekerjaan Umum dan Perumahan Rakyat (PUPR) conducted for 5 months. The activities involved providing assistance for house repairs or self-help housing construction in line with livable housing indicators.

- provided consulted to 47 aid recipients about livable home
- I have provided support to 47 aid recipients
- I conducted quality control and assurance for a total of 47 houses

PT. Mentari Prima Niaga - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

May 2022 - Jul 2022

Quality Control Engineering

My activities during my internship at PT. Mentari Prima Niaga. I was Assigned working as a Quality Control in the construction project of Walidah Mosque and Convention Hall at 'Aisyiyah University Yogyakarta.

- Lead to work processes and project stages on site
- · Lead 20 worker to do steel fabrication
- Lead 5 worker to do formwork before casting

Education Level

Universitas Muhammadiyah Yogyakarta - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Sep 2019 - Jul 2023

Bachelor Degree in Civil Engineering in, 3.81/4.00

- Final Year Project: Quality Control of the Construction of Self-Help Houses in Overcoming Uninhabitable Houses in Lampung Province
- Journal Publication: Quality Control of the Construction of Self-Help Houses in Overcoming Uninhabitable Houses in Lampung Province

Organisational and Project Experience

Multi-story building structural design project - Yogyakarta, Indonesia Jan 2021 Vice Chairman

- Assigning tasks and responsibilities and Creating a framework of tasks to be undertaken
- Creating initial calculations and planning using Microsoft Excel and Performing design and load input in the Etabs software application and Preparing the final report

On Job Training (HMS) - UMY, Yogyakarta

Dec 2019 - Jan 2020

Participant Member

- Training to lead a event
- · Prepare materials and tools needed for the event
- Responsible for the success of the event

Skills & Certificate Experience

- **Skills**: Microsoft Office, Etabs (basic), Sketchup (basic), ETABS (Predominate), Geo 5, Arcmap (Arcgis) (middle), and Autocad (middle). BIM Revit (middle)
- Training (2023): Operational Supervision of Mining for Mining Supervisors by CV Kita Kompeten
- Training (2023): Mine Planning di Tambang Batubara dan Nikel Open Pit by Miners Education
- Internship (2022): Field Facilitator in Program BSPS (Bantuan Stimulan Perumahan Swadaya) by Ditjen Kementerian PUPR
- Training (2024): Modeling and analysis of a two-story warehouse building structure